prativa.pokhrel95@gmail.com, linkedin.com/in/prativa-pokhrel

A full-stack Software Engineer with 4 years of professional experience in developing full-stack web application, optimizing processes and leading teams. Proficient in multiple programming languages and technical tools such as Ruby, JavaScript, Python, React, and Java. Experienced in scientific data analysis using Python and R.

phone: 3303978302

Skills:

Programming: Ruby, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Python, R, SQL, GraphQL,

Other Technical: React, NodeJS, GIT, Linux, Tableau, Docker, Codeship, Shopify, Redis, Postman

Education:

Master of Computing and Information Systems, Youngstown State University | May 2023

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering, Tribhuvan University | Nov 2016

Work Experience:

Graduate Research Assistant, Youngstown State University, OH | Aug 2021 – Present

- Scientific Data Analysis using Python and R with packages like scipy, scikit-learn, pandas and numpy, utilized parallel computing on Ohio Supercomputer servers.
- Carried out research on Machine Learning Hyperparameter Optimization Frameworks like Optuna and HyperOpt.

Software Engineer, Jyassa Technologies, Nepal | Mar 2020 – Aug 2021

- Optimized multiple large processes by 60 70% in processing time using GraphQL and re-designing.
- Led multiple teams of Quality Assurance and Software Engineers through different projects. Responsible for Code Quality, Code Reviews, Design Reviews, Code documentation and Design documentation for maintainability.

Software Engineer, Banba Group, Nepal | Dec 2016 – Oct 2019

- Developed and integrated RESTful APIs for Web and Mobile Applications.
- Carried out test-driven development with RSpec, Capybara, Selenium and achieved 100% test coverage.

Projects:

- Developed Admin portal using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and dockerized application with Docker for https://www.conx.co/
- Optimized search query using PostGresql, redesigned search page using ReactJS, implemented payment gateway with Braintree for https://www.camplify.com.au/
- Involved in generation of reports and dashboard using coffeescript, jQuery and generated API documentation with Swaggerdocs for https://shiftcare.com/
- Rebuilt software system by replacing a REST API with GraphQL https://apps.shopify.com/japan-order-csv

Conference Presentation:

- "Braintree Payment Gateway", Ruby Meet up Nepal, Nepal, 2017
- "Machine Learning Interpretability for Tabular Data", Flairs-35, US, 2022 and Diversity of Scholarship, Youngstown State University, US, 2022
- "A Comparison of AutoML Hyperparameter Optimization Tools for Tabular Data", OCWIC, US, 2023 and Diversity of Scholarship, Youngstown State University, US, 2023